A Guide to Graduate Council Minutes, 1958-1972: UA 0024
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Graduate Council Minutes,
1958-1972
Special Collections, James Madison University
Madison College Graduate Council
UA 0024
.66 cubic feet; 2 boxes
The Graduate Council Minutes, 1958-1972, are comprised of minutes of the Madison College Graduate Council.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open to research. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the James Madison University Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Acquisition Information
Present in cage in 1982 when Special Collections program began.
Administrative History
The Graduate Council was established in 1954 to administer Madison College's first graduate program, the Master of Arts in Education and the Master of Science in Education. The original Graduate Council was composed of the Dean of the College as chairman, the four divisional directors, and two additional members of the faculty.
When President Tyler Miller was inaugurated in 1949, he immediately began working on establishing a graduate program at Madison College. In 1951, President Miller coordinated with the University of Virginia to offer a graduate course during the Madison Summer Sessions. By 1954, after three years of study by a committee of the faculty, the State Board of Education authorized Madison College to award their own Masters degrees. During the first 1954-55 graduate session, 106 students enrolled in graduate courses, most of which were offered during summer sessions, special two-week "intersessions" and six-week graduate sessions. By 1972, Madison College graduate course offerings had expanded to include a Master in Business Administration, and graduate level coursework in other fields.
Scope and Content
The Graduate Council Minutes, 1958-1972, is comprised of fourteen folders of meeting minutes. Topics in the minutes include review and approval of degree candidates, general announcements, enrollment numbers, curriculum and program proposals, and other departmental matters. The 1958 Graduate Council members were Percy H. Warren (Dean of College), Mr. Bucher, Mr. Ikenberry, Mr. Mengebier, and Mr. Elmer L. Smith. The 1972 Graduate Council members were Dr. Sweigart (Assistant Provost for Graduate Studies), Dr. Blair, Dr. Bruce, Dr. Chappel, Dr. Crawford, Dr. Christiansen, Dr. Dickerson, Dr. Diller, Dr. Dingledine, Dr. D. Fox, Dr. D. Hall, Dr. Hinton, Dr. Ikenberry, Dr. Locke, Dr. McMurray, Dr. Trelawny, Dr. Wells, Dr. Bilksy, Dr. Caldwell, Dr. Cline, Dr. Davis, Dr. Mace, Dr. Ohlsson, Dr. Sanders and Dr. Smith.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically in fourteen folders.
Bibliography
Dingledine, Raymond C., Jr. "Madison College: the First Fifty Years, 1908-1958." Harrisonburg, VA: Madison College, 1959.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Madison College -- History; James Madison University -- History; Universities and colleges -- Graduate work -- History; Harrisonburg (Va.) -- History
Genre and Form Terms:
Minutes (administrative records)
- Minutes, 1958-1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Minutes, 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Minutes, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Minutes, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Minutes, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Minutes, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Minutes, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Minutes, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Minutes, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Minutes, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Minutes, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Minutes, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Minutes, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Minutes, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)